David Ryne Zear

+46 70 497 6166 | drzear@gmail.com | drzear.github.io | Gustav III:s Boulevard 6, Solna

ABOUT ME

I am an experienced analyst/developer with a proven track-record of developing and supporting business intelligence tools using a variety of software. My self-motivation allows me to work well both alone/remotely and as part of a team. During my time at Radisson I have provided results to a variety of stakeholders across the organization, ranging from ad-hoc analysis to full-stack web development. I love learning the newest technologies available.

SKILLS

Database MySQL, SQL Server, Clickhouse
Web HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular, React
Analysis Python, Excel, R, Power BI

WORK EXPERIENCE

Radisson Hotel Group

BI Revenue Management Developer EMEA Stockholm, Sweden Oct. 2019 - Present

- Model data in and maintain MySQL and Clickhouse databases.
- Create business intelligence dashboards using Angular (Typescript/HTML/CSS).
- Create new data pipelines from source to dashboard (e.g. source db -> RHG database -> model data -> deliver to front-end).
- Work from Stockholm as part of a remote geographically-distributed team that is based in Brussels.
- Collaborate with many levels and departments within organization.

Radisson Hotel Group

Data Analyst Stockholm, Sweden Jan. 2018 - Oct. 2019

- Created internal system status website that monitored and reported data quality to end users using Angular framework for front-end and an Express and MySQL back-end.
- Scrum Master in data analyst team's Agile working environment.
- Designed and built Meetings and Events pricing tool used throughout Northern Europe.
- Responsible for MySQL development and data warehouse maintenance.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to create and maintain tools to increase operational efficiencies, aid in business monitoring, and facilitate revenue management.

Pearson PLC

Scoring Supervisor Iowa City, IA USA July 2015 - May 2017

- Analyzed scoring patterns to identify problematic trends and ensure that students received the correct score.
- Supervised work of other scorers.

Integrated DNA Technologies

Production Scientist II Coralville, IA USA July 2010 - July 2014

- Analyzed finished DNA/RNA data to ensure correct product was produced using a variety of analysis tools.
- Troubleshot production issues using Microsoft AX database software in combination with Excel.
- Trained colleagues on all departmental processes.

FORMAL EDUCATION

University of Iowa Iowa City, IA USA Bachelor of Science, Biology (2007) Dean's List

LANGUAGES

English - Native German - Conversant

Swedish - Basic